attendanceondemand.com 2018-11-25

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to Attendance on Demand, Inc. ("Attendance on Demand"). Please read the following carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your personal information and how we treat it.

By accessing or using our website ("Site"), the ESS Mobile App or the Mobile Manager App (each, an “App”) or the products or services offered on or through the Site or an App ("Services"), you agree to this policy.

In order to improve Services, our Site may gather information about you and the pages you visit. This policy explains how this may happen, how we may use information collected about you and how you can contact us to request correction of such information.

## Personal Data Information Collected

In order to access the Services, you may be asked to provide information that allows you to be identified as a particular person, such as your name, your address or phone number, your email address and your company ("Personal Data").

By voluntarily providing us with Personal Data, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including without limitation, your acknowledgement and agreement that such Personal Data may be transferred from your current location to offices and servers of Attendance on Demand and/or those third party providers with whom we have a relationship, including analytics and advertising partners ("Service Providers"), and to our affiliates, employees and contractors located in the United States and other countries.

## Other Information

Cookies: Attendance on Demand, or its Service Providers may send a cookie to your computer or use web beacons to gather statistical information. Neither cookies nor web beacons personally identify you. A cookie is a piece of data that a website can send to your browser, which is then stored on your computer as an anonymous tag that identifies your computer. When a visitor accesses certain pages on the Site an anonymous notice of that visit is generated which may be processed by us or by our Service Providers. Web beacons work in conjunction with cookies to let us know what portions of the Site are of interest to you and to help us provide you with tailored information from our Site. We use the information primarily to provide you with a personalized Internet experience that delivers information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you.

If you never provide us with Personal Data, then your visits to our Site – despite us using cookies or web beacons – are anonymous. We don't know the actual person linked with the cookie or web beacon.

If you do provide Personal Data, then we could potentially link that with your cookie, then gather the visits with web beacons and understand how you personally have acted when visiting the Site.

If you do provide Personal Data, then we could potentially link that with your cookie, then gather the visits with web beacons and understand how you personally have acted when visiting the Site.

Browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is being sent. If you turn off cookies, web beacon technology will still detect anonymous visits, but the notices they generate cannot be associated with other anonymous information or Personal Data and are disregarded. 

GPS: When you use the App, we also collect global positioning (GPS) data through your mobile devices.

## How We May Use Your Information

We will only disclose your Personal Data and other information collected on our Site or through the use of the Services in one of the following circumstances:

  1. With your consent.
  2. To our employees, contractors, affiliates, business partners and Service Providers relating to the Services offered on or through the Site, each of which are under contractual obligations to protect the confidentiality of such information.
  3. Pursuant to applicable law or regulation or in response to a subpoena or an order of a court or government agency.
  4. To establish, exercise, or defend against legal claims of an individual or Attendance on Demand, including in order to protect the safety of an individual or to protect Attendance on Demand's rights and/or property.
  5. To a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of Attendance on Demand: (i) in the event of a reorganization or restructuring, or (ii) for use and processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  6. In connection with a change of ownership or control, including, without limitation, a merger or an acquisition of any or all of Attendance on Demand's business assets.

## Security

Attendance on Demand implements a variety of security measures to protect your Personal Data. Your Personal Data is contained behind secured networks. When you access your Personal Data, we offer the use of a secure server. Any sensitive information you supply is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our database.

## Third Party Monitoring

Third-party vendors, including Google [(www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), show Attendance on Demand ads on sites across the Internet. Third-party vendors, including Google, may use cookies and/or web beacons to serve ads based on past visits to our website. You may opt out of a third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

## Privacy Policies of Third Parties

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information by Attendance on Demand. Other websites that may be accessible through this Site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Our affiliates and business partners have their own privacy policies too. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy statement/policies provided by all third parties prior to providing them with information.

## Notice to Residents of Countries outside the United States

Attendance on Demand is headquartered in the United States of America. Your personal information may be accessed by or transferred to the United States or to our affiliates or third party elsewhere in the world. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to this transfer. We will always use commercial reasonable measures to protect the privacy of your personal information, regardless of where it is processed or stored.

## Children Under 13

We do not intentionally collect information from children under 13 on the Site. If you are aware that a child under 13 has provided us with information and you so notify us, we shall promptly remove such information.

## Updating Your Information

You can update your information in the following ways:  
By postal mail to: Attention: Privacy, Attendance on Demand, Inc., 22300 Haggerty Road, Northville, MI 48167, by phone at 248-476-0008 or to opt-out utilize the unsubscribe option at the bottom of your newsletter.

Attendance on Demand, Inc. hosts data for customers using its labor management service. When customers use biometric time clocks, finger or hand templates (“Templates”) are also stored. Some states, including Illinois and Texas, have statutes governing biometric information. Templates are digitally-converted representations of geometric measurements of the hand or fingerprint. Templates may or may not be deemed to be biometric information under such statutes. Attendance on Demand’s policy is designed to protect and store the Templates in accordance with applicable standards and biometric information laws.

## Storage of Biometric Data

Templates are stored in time clocks and in the customer’s Attendance on Demand database. They can be deleted at the time clock, with authorized access, and through the Attendance on Demand service by an authorized system user. Templates are included in production backups of Attendance on Demand customer databases. Attendance on Demand will not sell, lease, trade, or otherwise profit from an individual’s Templates and shall only disclose, re-disclose or disseminate an individual’s Templates with necessary consents or as may be required by law.

## Routine Maintenance of Biometric Data

Customers are responsible for complying with applicable standards and laws. For example, under the Illinois law, customers must delete an individual’s biometric data when the initial purpose for collecting or obtaining the data has been satisfied or within three years of the individual’s last interaction with the customer, whichever occurs first. When an employment relationship ends, the customer terminates the employee through the Attendance on Demand service by changing the employee’s status. The customer should also delete the Template when the employee’s status is set to Terminated. This causes the Template to be deleted from the Attendance on Demand database and the time clock (at the time clock’s next synchronization).

## Maintenance and Storage of Backups and Archives

Backups of active customer databases are automated and take place on an incremental hourly, daily, weekly and quarterly basis. These production backups are kept for a maximum of one year. After one year, they are destroyed.

Authorized support personnel from Attendance on Demand, Inc. may occasionally backup or copy a system for the purposes of testing and troubleshooting. It is Attendance on Demand’s policy that these backups be deleted when they are no longer needed. As a precaution, all manual backups are destroyed after one year.

Attendance on Demand, Inc. archives databases of clients that are no longer using the Attendance on Demand service. As part of the archive process, all Templates are deleted.

## Security of Biometric Information

Attendance on Demand, Inc. takes great care with all employee data, including Templates and such care is within the reasonable standard of care for this industry. Attendance on Demand stores, transmits, and protects the Templates in a manner that is the same or more protective than it stores, transmits, and protects other confidential or sensitive information. Templates are transmitted with encryption. Access to employee information is protected through access rights and password authorization. Biometric information cannot be imported or exported from the system. In addition, Attendance on Demand’s hosting environment and backup storage are protected from unauthorized access by physical and digital security measures.

This Attendance on Demand, Inc. Biometric Information Policy should not be construed as legal advice. Contact your legal counsel for clarification and/or advice regarding this and other state laws and regulations.

© 2014-2018, Attendance on Demand, Inc.
